justcauseit.com 2009-07-17

# Privacy Policy | JUST CAUSE (beta)

JUST CAUSE is committed to protecting the private information that our users give us. This privacy policy explains what personal information is collected, when and how it is used, disclosed and protected with respect to our web site located at [www.justcauseit.com](http://www.justcauseit.com/ "Linkification: http://www.justcauseit.com") (the "Site"). By using the Site, you accept the policy, even as modified by us periodically. Please carefully review this policy so you understand our data privacy practices. 

## What is Personal Information?  

Personal information is information that specifically identifies an individual, including but not limited to, name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, or other account number, and information about that individual's activities when directly linked to that person such as information about use of the Site. Personal information may also include demographic information such as birth date, gender, location and personal preferences you give us during routine use of the site. Personal information does not include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of products, services or customers, from which individual customer identities have been removed. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service, but it will not include personal information through which you can be identified. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and our users' needs so that we can better consider new features or otherwise tailor our Site. 

## Information We Collect  

We collect personal information in a number of ways when you visit our web site. For example, we collect personal information when you: (1) register and set up an account; (2) sign up for any of our e-mail newsletters; (3) post content on your blog; (4) join a cause or discussion group (5) create or RSVP for an event (6) invite others to join your event or cause (7) contact us by e-mail for any reason; (8) make a transaction through our site. When you visit our web site, some information is also automatically collected, such as your computer's Internet Protocol (IP) address, your computer's operating system, the browser type, the address of a referring web site, and the time and date of your visit and purchases. We treat this information as personal information if we combine it with or link it to any of the identifying information mentioned above. Otherwise, it is used in the aggregate only. 

## How We Use Collected Information  

In general, we use personal information to process your requests and provide you with service, and connect you with information, organizations, individuals, products or services we think will be of interest. When we use personal information in our marketing efforts, we provide you with options (See Control of Personal Information below) and do not disclose the information to third parties except as described in this Policy. Personal information provided online may be linked together or merged with other personal information so that we may better understand your needs and inform you about our products or services and those of our partners. In addition, if we receive information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, we may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In either case, this Policy governs this information. 

## Content   

We encourage you to speak your mind, offer and share information. We believe in freedom of speech, and we believe that free speech is necessary for the productive dialogue that will improve our collective understanding of the world around us. As such, we encourage you to explore your own ideas, and those of others. You understand that anything you say on the Site is your responsibility and does not, in any way, represent the views of JUST CAUSE. You will be held legally responsible for your words and their presence on our site does not imply any sort of endorsement or protection of you, by us. 

While we encourage a vibrant dialogue, we will not accept or condone any language, event or cause that is considered threatening in any way to another user, organization, corporation or individual on the Site or in the physical world. Advocating violence of any sort against people or properties is grounds for immediate removal of the objectionable listing. Repeated offense will result in the termination of your account. 

Unless otherwise selected, your blogs, comments, events and causes are displayed publicly. Your member name is automatically displayed with comments you publish, and if other members choose to, they can receive email notifications of your publications or publish their own comments to your reviews. 

We, and our licensees, can republish your content as described in the JUST CAUSE terms of use. We publish review all content and use it to develop aggregate ratings, personalize site views and other site features. 

## Email   

If you send emails through our site, your email will include your email address and any personal message you include. However, these emails aren't private communications. We do not retain, in any easily-retrievable way, the addresses you are emailing. You may not use these tools to send spam or content that violates the user agreement. 

You may not harvest personal data (including email addresses) from the site, and specifically you may not use email addresses displayed on the site to ask users to join or contribute to your services. 

## Security  

We have put into place reasonable security measures in an effort to protect personal information while it is under our control. Your account information is accessible online only through the use of a password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of our web site by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. 

## Control of Your Information  

We give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and to view, correct or delete your personal information. 

If you do not want to receive e-mail from us, you can; (a) alter your preferences accordingly; or (b) follow the opt-out instructions at the bottom of any email you receive from us. If you want to view, correct or delete your personal information, you can access your information online by clicking the "My Just Cause" link. We may share personal information with third-party vendors who assist us in performing functions necessary to operate our business. These functions may include, without limitation, Website hosting, credit card transaction processing and data entry. We limit the information shared with our third-party vendors to that which we believe is necessary to carry out those functions. Moreover, we require them to comply with our privacy practices, and not to use the information for other purposes except as required by law. We are not responsible for any failure on their part to comply with our privacy practices, nor are we responsible for any additional information you provide directly to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them. 

In addition, we may disclose personal information in the good faith belief that we are lawfully authorized to do so, or that doing so is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process or authorities, respond to any claims, or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of JUST CAUSE, our users, our employees or the public. Information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed or transferred as part of, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets or acquisition. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personal information when posting reviews or other content to the Site, this information may be collected and used by others. You agree that we shall bear no responsibility for any such disclosures. We recommend you be cautious in giving out personal information to others in public online forums. 

Lastly, if any law enforcement agency approaches JUST CAUSE with appropriate documents that show reason to believe you are using the JUST CAUSE site to commit a crime, we will cooperate and give them your information. 

## Cookies  

Cookies: Cookies are small text files placed on your hard drive by a web site when you visit. These files identify your computer and record your preferences and other data about your visit so that when you return to the site, the site knows who you are and can personalize your visit. In general, we use cookies to collect information so that we can determine how to improve our sites by seeing which areas and features are most popular; to personalize the site, to improve the site experience and to complete transactions you have requested. Most browsers automatically accept cookies as the default setting. You can modify the setting to reject cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit by editing browser options. If you decide not to accept our cookies, you will still be able to access those parts of our site available to the general public but you may not be able to use some of the site's features or services and you may have a less satisfactory experience. 

## Use of our Web Site by Children  

We encourage parents to take an active interest in their children's use of the Internet. We do not intend to collect information from children who are under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 you should not provide information on our web site. 

We do, however, want to encourage children to take an active role in improving the world around them. Please work with your children to help them research and make change. The JUST CAUSE site should be a safe place to do that, as a family. 

## Links to Other Sites  

Our web site contains links to other web sites. Any personal information you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. Except as described above, we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of web sites to which we link. Links from our web site to third parties or to other sites are provided for your convenience. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information. 

## Comments or Concerns  

We welcome your feedback. If you have any comments or concerns about this privacy policy or would like to contact us for any reason, you may reach us at [info@justcauseit.com](mailto:info@justcauseit.com "Linkification: mailto:info@justcauseit.com"). 

## Data Changes  

If you terminate your account or delete/change your data or content, we usually update our live databases immediately. However, some data may update more slowly, and some old data may remain in our archives and records. Also, we may be unable to propagate changes to partners who receive your data or content. If your account is being terminated or suspended, we may maintain some data to prevent re-registration. 

## Policy Changes  

We reserve the right to change this Policy at any time. We may use personal information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in this privacy policy. If our privacy practices change we will post the policy changes to our web site and notify you by indicating the date the privacy policy was last updated. We will also provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. We encourage you to check back at our web site periodically if you are concerned about how your information is used.
